audiocastle.me 2016-10-17

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

_Privacy Policy  _  

The purpose of the AudioCastle Privacy Policy is to inform our listeners about the information that we collect, how we use that information and the ways listeners can control how that information is used or shared. The entire policy can be found below. To make it a bit easier to digest our Privacy Policy, we want to highlight some key items. 

You have significant control over the information that is shared with other AudioCastle users and the public through the privacy settings for your profile: 

• We do not sell or give your email address to other companies for their marketing purposes without your permission. 

• Information that you post in our community and through our social networking features is available to members of the public. 

• We collect information about the tracks played on AudioCastle to make sure artists and copyright owners get paid. We must report listening information to copyright licensing agencies. These reports contain aggregated data only, and do not identify individual listeners. 

• We collect information about the stations, tracks and artists you listen to, thumb-up, thumb-down or bookmark, and the information you provide about yourself, to personalize your AudioCastle experience through suggestions of music, artists and other content you may enjoy, as well as advertisements and social networking features. This information is publicly available, unless your profile is marked private. 

• Anyone can search for, and listen to, stations that you create on AudioCastle. If your profile is private, then other people can find one of your stations in a search, but your profile will not be linked to that station; however, if someone enters your entire email address into our search system, they will be able to see a list of all the stations created under that email address. 

This summary is not the complete picture, so please read the AudioCastle Privacy Policy below in its entirety to learn more about the information that we collect, how we use and share this information, and your options to control how that information is used or shared. 

AUDIOCASTLE NETWORK, INC. 

PRIVACY POLICY 

(EFFECTIVE AS OF December 20, 2012) 

This Privacy Policy is effective as of January 30, 2012, for AudioCastle Media, Inc. and its subsidiaries ("AudioCastle ", "we", "us" or "our"). It applies to the United States operations for the AudioCastle ® internet radio service (the "Service") that we offer through our website located at [www.audiocastle.net](http://www.audiocastle.net/) , supported mobile devices, consumer electronics devices, devices connected to or installed in an automobile, automotive sound systems and other mechanisms. 

We will continue to evaluate this Privacy Policy against new technologies, business practices, and our listeners' needs, and may make changes to the Privacy Policy accordingly. Please check this page periodically for updates. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post the updated Privacy Policy here and notify you by email or by means of a notice on our website. 

The types of information we collect 

There are several areas where you can submit information to us, and some features that automatically collect information from the listeners of our Service and visitors to our website. 

Information you give us: 

To enable you to enjoy certain features of our Service, we collect certain types of information, including personally identifiable information, during your interactions with our Service. For example, we collect information when you: 

• Register to use our Service; 

• Enter information in your Profile, including the people you are following and the people whom you allow to follow you; 

• Post comments on other AudioCastle listeners' pages, use community and social networking features that are part of our Service, or send us email; 

• Participate in polls, contests, or other features of the Service, or respond to offers or advertisements on the Service; and 

• Sign up to receive email newsletters. 

When you register, we ask you to provide certain information, which includes (but may not be limited to) your email address, birth year, gender, and zip code, as well as a password for your listener account. If you choose to subscribe to fee-based portions of the Service, you will also be asked to provide (at a minimum) your name and credit card information. 

Information we receive from third parties 

We may receive information about you from third parties and store it in our databases with other information (including personally identifiable information) that you provide to us. Some examples of these third parties are listed below: 

• Service partners and advertisers that make features available through the Service; 

• Service partners through whom we allow registered listeners to access the Service; 

• Marketing companies that create professional marketing lists or sell other marketing data; 

• Other websites or applications that you have registered to use, or that people you know have registered to use, when we allow those websites or applications to interact through the Service to provide personalized services to you. In some cases, those websites or applications may automatically provide us with information about you to facilitate personalization unless you use the controls available on those websites or applications to opt-out of such sharing. 

AudioCastle is not responsible for, and will assume no liability, if a business partner or other entity collects, uses or shares any information about you in violation of its own privacy policy or applicable law. 

Information that we receive from other listeners 

We may collect information about you from people who have stored information about you when they elect to use our social networking or community features, or when they enable connectivity with another website or application where they have stored such information. For instance, your friends may have stored information about you in places such as their friend lists, address books, or photos on our website and other sites with which the Service interacts. 

We also collect your email address when people you know share a station with you, but we will not add your name to any of our mailing lists as a result of this feature. 

Automatic Data Collection 

Listening Activity: AudioCastle keeps track of your listening activity. AudioCastle uses software that is designed to ensure that artists and copyright owners receive applicable royalties for the tracks you hear. This software identifies and counts the tracks you have accessed. AudioCastle also collects information about stations, artists and tracks you have listened to or in which you have expressed an interest for advertising and social networking features. 

Service partners: When you access the Service through a service partner, we may add select aspects of your registration information (such as your email address), so that we can identify which of our service partners or other sign-in pages to send to you when you log on to the Service. 

Information about your computer or device: We may also collect information about the computer, mobile or other devices you use to access and listen to the Service. For example, our servers receive and record information about your computer and browser, including potentially your IP address, browser type, and other software or hardware information. If you access the Service from a mobile or other device, we may collect a unique device identifier assigned to that device or other transactional information for that device. 

• Tracking technology: We use what are commonly called "cookies," a small data string our server writes to your hard drive, and other tracking technology to help us manage and track your interaction with AudioCastle Services. These technologies collect non-personally identifiable..

 _How we use cookies?_

A cookie is a small piece of text sent to your browser by a website you visit. It helps the website to remember information about your visit, like your preferred language and other settings. That can make your next visit easier and the site more useful to you. Cookies play an important role. Without them, using the web would be a much more frustrating experience. We use cookies for many purposes. We use them, for example, to remember your safe search preferences, to make the ads you see more relevant to you, to count how many visitors we receive to a page, to help you sign up for our services and to protect your data.
